<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>What explains poor growth in the UK? The IMF thinks it's fiscal policy</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="cityspiders"/>
        <Person nickname="Mark Allan"/>
        <Person nickname="avraam jack"/>
        <Person nickname="greenwichite"/>
        <Person nickname="iffatali"/>
        <Person nickname="keti"/>
        <Person nickname="Sam Lucas"/>
        <Person nickname="Rihana Gomez"/>
        <Person nickname="Macky2024"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="cityspiders">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="9 October 2012 09:47">&amp;quot;Will our government, and those of the eurozone, do the same?&amp;quot;This is what we like to call &amp;quot;a rhetorical question&amp;quot;, correct?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Mark Allan">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="9 October 2012 13:08">I&amp;#39;m not an esteemed economist,I drive trains for a living but one doesn&amp;#39;t need to be to work it out that you don&amp;#39;t create growth by putting people out of work. You don&amp;#39;t go around putting the fear of God into people by telling them we&amp;#39;re bankrupt,the card is maxed out etc. Then wonder why no one will spend any money on the high street.They&amp;#39;ve created this climate of fear that has killed &amp;quot;the animal spirits&amp;quot; according to Keynes.Their answer? More of the same,and even more cuts to the least who can afford it.This is madness and its oft quoted but the lunatics really have taken over the asylum!</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="avraam jack">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="10 October 2012 15:24">.    A large part of the problem  is that credible economists do not seem interested in running for Public Office.    If every  economist good enough to be working at a university ran for office,  enough would win that we would see a great improvement in economic policy.    Why do economists fear and lawyers love politics?         Avraam J. Dectis.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="greenwichite">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="12 October 2012 06:15">Dear Mr. Portes,Krugman&amp;#39;s response to the paper hinted that you will be debating together at some point next week. (Here is the link: http://krugman.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/10/09/deleveraging-shocks-and-the-multiplier-sort-of-wonkish/) I was wondering if you could provide any information about when and where this is taking place? As a final-year undergrad student in Econ at Bristol I&amp;#39;d be very excited about the opportunity to attend. Thanks!Adam</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="iffatali">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="21 November 2012 05:31">All travel has its advantages. If the passenger visits better countries, he may learn to improve his own. And if fortune carries him to worse, he may learn to enjoy it.Flights to Addis AbabaCheap Flights to Addis AbabaCheap Air Tickets to Addis Ababa</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="keti">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="19 February 2013 10:28">As many other employed people I also had several credits. It is better to have one concern than many, so I made the decision about restructuring of the credit. I used http://creditcard-consolidationloan.com/ service to effectively cover my debts and pay significantly less every month. They will help you to find preferred payment schedule and interest fee.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Sam Lucas">
            <Utterance genid="7" time="3 April 2013 00:11">Chartering for air cargo is available for all sizes depending on the client&amp;#39;s needs. The use of smaller aircrafts may be more apparent in accessing more rustic areas due to space constraint to accommodate larger ones.luxury private jets Toronto</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Rihana Gomez">
            <Utterance genid="8" time="11 April 2013 07:09">If every economist good enough to be working at a university ran for office, enough would win that we would see a great improvement in economic policy.You YouTube</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Macky2024">
            <Utterance genid="9" time="14 April 2013 23:45">The cost of chartering a private jet shouldn&amp;#39;t be the main concern in your mind, instead you should research the company you plan to use especially their reputation. You can do this by searching for them on the internet. A standard search should give you a number of results. Look at testimonials from customers and get a feel about the company. air charter</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
