<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>Believing in "miracles"? Self-defeating austerity and self-financing stimulus</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Robert Andersen"/>
        <Person nickname="Simon"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Robert Andersen">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="11 March 2013 06:02">You wrote: &amp;#39;I am not sure whether the Prime Minister is correct in his description of Labour&amp;#39;s policy&amp;#39;yet maintain you are not politically biased. Interesting.Next, you write; &amp;#39;In other words, under current circumstances, it&amp;#39;s quite plausible that borrowing more could lead to borrowing less (over the longer term)&amp;#39; based on research from Wren lewis, itself based on numbers crunched by Larry Summers. Now, at this point, I felt compelled to put down my cup of Earl grey. Larry Summers??!?!? So to sum up, we should borrow more now because the US has shown that their extra borrowing in the past has led to lesser borrowing currently. Interesting.Perhaps in your coming pieces we may hear your thoughts on the US fiscal cliff and potential impacts on the UK?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Simon">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="11 March 2013 08:59">JonathanAs you say (in reply to Robert), both the Green Budget by the IFS and the Treasury concur with the findings of the NIESR, Wren-Lewis and DeLong &amp;amp; Summers. So, is there any reason why the IFS or indeed the Treasury have not yet publicly pointed out David Cameron&amp;#39;s latest example of...how can I say it...applying austerity to the truth, in a similar way that Robert Chote at the OBR did on Friday?Or is it because the OBR need to &amp;#39;be seen&amp;#39; to be independent, and did so by the quick rebuke on Friday? In any case, since there appears no supporting evidence in his favour,I expect similar &amp;#39;innaccuracies&amp;#39; from Cameron over time as he needs to say whatever it takes to continue(justify)his policies, which ought to be more publicly recognized as being the means of achieving their ultimate, ideological goal of shrinking the state; irrespective of evidence, facts and economic hardship caused.   </Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
