<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>Faith-based economics at the Treasury Committee</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Tom Freeman"/>
        <Person nickname="Steven Clarke"/>
        <Person nickname="crasshopper"/>
        <Person nickname="keti"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Tom Freeman">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="15 November 2012 06:32">It&amp;#39;s sad, because even though &amp;#39;credibility&amp;#39; is by its nature a vague and subjective concept, we do have a simple indicator, regularly published by the Treasury, that covers the relevant kind of credibility.The independent forecasts of government borrowing show how credible people find the fiscal plans. And, as you and I and others have said time and again, these forecasts have got worse and worse, meaning that the government&amp;#39;s plans are seen as less and less credible.And yet, as this has happened, the cost of government borrowing has come down. Therefore credibility can&amp;#39;t be the explanation for cheaper borrowing.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Steven Clarke">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="15 November 2012 11:54">Jesse comes badly out of this. He seems to go straight into an &amp;#39;ad hominem&amp;#39; attack on you, suggesting your considered economic views are driven by political animus against the Government. You did well to stand your ground.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="crasshopper">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="27 November 2012 23:11">Seems like an overly inflammatory title. Show me an economic forecast that doesn&amp;#39;t use assumptions and we can start referring to the others as &amp;quot;faith-based&amp;quot;.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="keti">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="20 February 2013 03:34">As many other employed people I also had several credits. It is better to have one concern than many, so I made the decision about restructuring of the credit. I used http://creditcard-consolidationloan.com/ service to effectively cover my debts and pay significantly less every month. They will help you to find preferred payment schedule and interest fee.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
