<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>David Goodhart's British fantasy</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Theo Clifford"/>
        <Person nickname="Andrew Green"/>
        <Person nickname="Martin Wolf"/>
        <Person nickname="Chris Bertram"/>
        <Person nickname="Sue Lukes"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Theo Clifford">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="27 March 2013 15:03">I question the extent to which immigration policy was primarily driven by an economic perspective.If that is the case, why was immigration so tightly controlled?Surely net migration of 400k or 600k would have been much better for everyone, if the Treasury was really running the show?Rather I think the 2000s immigration story is that the EU forced the government to accept more migrants that it wouldn&amp;#39;t otherwise have allowed, but couldn&amp;#39;t really restrict. After all I don&amp;#39;t have a figure on how much of the UK&amp;#39;s migration over this period was from A8 countries but I assume it was a very substantial proportion. And of course low-skilled migration from outside the EU was all but banned around the same time - perhaps that&amp;#39;s a better indicator of the government&amp;#39;s true stance.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Andrew Green">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="28 March 2013 04:29">Mr.Portes now says that he agrees that GDP per head is a better measure of any benefit of immigration. Unfortunately, the previous government, in which he was an influential official, repeatedly referred to the &amp;#163;6 billion benefit to GDP without acknowledging that, after allowing for the population growth, this amounted to about 0.1 % per year for GDP per head.  Indeed the House of Lords Select Committee report in April 2008 found no evidence that &amp;quot;net immigration generates significant economic benefits for the existing population&amp;quot; - a conclusion since studiously ignored by the immigration lobby among whom he is a leading voice.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Martin Wolf">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="28 March 2013 13:06">Aggregate GDP is, as I frequently noted at the time, a ludicrous measure of the benefits of immigration. That the Treasury used it was scandalous. Indeed, if that were the goal, elimination of controls on immigration would have been the right policy. Thus, David is quite right to point out that the implication of the government&amp;#39;s favourite measure was indeed that immigration restrictions should be eliminated, because that would have maximised GDP.Leave that absurd position aside. The question, then, is what weight should be put on the welfare of future immigrants. If the weight is very much higher than zero, then one is getting ever closer to the cosmopolitan welfare position that David is describing. So what was (and now should) the weight be, Jonathan?To put it in the context of your debate with David, let us agree that UK immigration policy is not concerned with the welfare of Burundi. But what is the value it places on the welfare of the Burundians who will arrive, as a result of a liberal policyI would argue that this weight should be zero. Under a zero weight on the welfare of future immigrants (surely the position of most British citizens), the policy question becomes not what is the impact on GDP per head, or productivity per worker, but the impact of immigrants (of different kinds) on GDP per head (and its distribution) for those already in the UK. That was never the criterion used by the previous government, so far as I know. </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Chris Bertram">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="29 March 2013 03:23">&amp;quot;I would argue that this weight should be zero&amp;quot;Well maybe you would, but you haven&amp;#39;t given any reasons, unless we are supposed to deduce them from your parenthetical and unevidenced reference to what most British people think. The idea that states should only be concerned with the well-being of their own citizens is completely contrary to what the UK is signed up for in may cases (for example the Refugee Convention) and would be an insurmountable obstacle to dealing with problems like climate change.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Sue Lukes">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="29 March 2013 04:33">Surely one of the many problems here is the jump from some idea of this &amp;quot;zero weight&amp;quot; as an analytical tool used in relation to all migrants to a policy applied to individuals. Becasue obviously once you average it out one v rich person (a footballer?) &amp;quot;cancels out&amp;quot; lots of poor people who might need welfare.  But you cannot run an immigration policy on that basis.  And, of course, no-one knows what will happen to someone who migrates.  The footballer may have a car crash and require permanent care, the penniless refugee found a business and contribute millions. The main problem I have though is that people who propose &amp;quot;zero weight&amp;quot; etc are essentially saying that a &amp;quot;migrant&amp;quot; remains different and somehow obliged to the state forever. It is an abstract way of saying it is acceptable to refuse benefits/housing/healthcare/education to anyone who looks or talks different in case they are a migrant. Thus Cameron quotes the CORE figures to say 9% of new social housing lettings last year &amp;quot;went to migrants&amp;quot;. No they did not. They went to non-British citizens (who constitute 9% of the population so on the face of it no unfairness indicated there).  They went to the Irishman who arrived aged 2 and finally went tinot sheltered housing aged 70 last year. They went to the Flilipino nurse who has lived and worked here for 15 years and does not have the money to pay for citizenship for herlself and her children. They went to the Somali bus driver who got refugee status in 1986. All &amp;quot;migrants&amp;quot; in the sense they are not British citizens. Saying they should not get services looks to me like old fashioned racism, just re-emerging under the cover of valuing citizenship over other factors like contribution, neighbourliness, decency?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Martin Wolf">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="29 March 2013 04:48">My view is that we have obligations to those who are in the UK. Those obligations do not take one-zero form. They increase with the level of attachment. Citizens come first. But others have clear rights. The nature and extent of these rights and obligations is clearly a legitimate matter for political discussion and disagreement. But I want to be clear. My view that potential immigrants have nearly zero weight in deciding immigration policy does not mean that actual immigrants have nearly zero weight. They definitely do not. I don&amp;#39;t think someone who has been here a day is entitled to housing benefit. But I would have a very different view of someone who has worked here for 10 years.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
