<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>We've got the deficit down by a quarter? No, a third! (updated)</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Ruben Starkadder"/>
        <Person nickname="Simon"/>
        <Person nickname="kpeter778"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Ruben Starkadder">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="22 March 2013 03:15">Exquisite.  When I hear a politician say these words I know that I am either be asleep and dreaming, or dead and in heaven.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Simon">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="22 March 2013 07:47">As you note, &amp;quot;most of the deficit reduction has come from cutting public sector net investment (spending on schools, roads, hospitals, etc) roughly in half.&amp;quot;No wonder the government doesn&amp;#39;t elaborate very publicly on  precisely how the deficit reduction has been achieved, since slashing public investment in schools, roads, hospitals may be done all too easily, simply by the stroke of a pen. To do so hardly requires much imagination, resourcefulness or economic skill. In continuing to boast of the reduction but without actually informing us of the extremely damaging way that it was achieved appears to suggest that it is the result of great skill, creativity and economic wizardry on the part of the government.Aside from the government&amp;#39;s intellectual dishonesty, more importantly what is the long-term economic damage to the country thanks to such a large reduction in public sector net investment spending? Can it be accurately quantified?Kind regardsSimon   </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="kpeter778">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="10 April 2013 17:57">bespokeleads.com provides online financial lead generation sales lead services.The lead investor is an individual entity or an investor interested in the identity of potential participants.Now we provide better service in local and international site.www.bespokeleads.com</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
