<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>Recessions and recoveries: a historical perspective (updated April 9, 2013)</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="CharlesJ"/>
        <Person nickname="obelix"/>
        <Person nickname="Jon Danzig"/>
        <Person nickname="Jack Allen"/>
        <Person nickname="Jayarava"/>
        <Person nickname="GreenWorld"/>
        <Person nickname="Julian Janssen"/>
        <Person nickname="Robert Andersen"/>
        <Person nickname="Aditya"/>
        <Person nickname="Richard Britton"/>
        <Person nickname="hajjandumrah"/>
        <Person nickname="Stephan White"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="CharlesJ">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="9 April 2012 05:33">Ass far as the private domestic sector is concerned, the economy will remain in depression for as long as the government continues to act with pro-cyclical fiscal policy - by not filling the output gap with government net spending.Exports won&amp;#39;t save us either for two reasons:a) many of our trading partners are not filling their output gaps either.b) many exporters also rely on sales to the private domestic sector too.With austerity at home and abroad, some exporters are alikely to become insolvent as well.Kind Regards</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="obelix">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="27 May 2012 08:23">By many measures, the UK entered a depression after World War I and never recovered before the World War II.  Yes, the UK spent the entire inter-war period in a depression.  Because of this, the graph in the post is profoundly misleading.  The author picks some unimportant blip (year 1930) in the middle of the two decade depression and calls it the starting point of the depression, whereas the true starting point of the UK depression was around 1919.   Surely the author of this blog understands this by now and therefore I am forced to conclude that he is intentionally attempting mislead his readers.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Jon Danzig">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="28 July 2012 14:33">At a debate about the future of the UK, I asked government member, Jo Johnson, MP, brother of London Mayor Boris, if Britain could be a number one economy again.  He said no, because the UK only has a population of around 60 million.  This doesn&amp;#39;t make sense to me, as Australia only has a population of around 23 million, and yet the IMF recently predicted that Australia would be the best performing major advanced economy in the world over the next two years.  Why not the UK?To see the YouTube video of my question and Mr Johnson&amp;#39;s reply go to:http://youtu.be/IpvOOqMd6Ww     (55 seconds)</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Jack Allen">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="5 August 2012 06:56">What does this chart look like for indicators such as GDP/capita, median income or youth employment-youth population ratio? I imagine similarly depressing, if not more so.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Jayarava">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="7 August 2012 13:09">As a matter of interest what is the margin of error on these estimates? And why are they not more widely reported?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="GreenWorld">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="9 August 2012 15:10">Hang on, does this mean we are in a Depression now?  That would be I would venture to say rather bad news.  When I think of an economic depression, I&amp;#39;d be more likely to think about Greece or Spain.  Whilst we would not want to understate the problems in the UK economy, we are in substantially better shape then the Greeks or the Spanish.alternative investments</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Julian Janssen">
            <Utterance genid="7" time="12 August 2012 20:29">Fed subsidizing low interest rates on federal debt?  Silly argument.http://socialmacro.blogspot.com/2012/08/fed-subsidizing-low-interest-rates-on.html </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Robert Andersen">
            <Utterance genid="8" time="11 December 2012 10:59">&amp;#39;Just as talk about a &amp;quot;double-dip recession&amp;quot; after the unusually bad second quarter growth figures was overdone, so was the euphoria about Britain &amp;quot;surging out of recession&amp;quot; after the third quarter figures. &amp;#39;well, er the double dip prediction after Q2 numbers for now is wrong. As for q3 numbers we don&amp;#39;t know. So I don&amp;#39;t know;1) which euphoria you are referring to, and2) how you can know we won&amp;#39;t get another period of growth.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Aditya">
            <Utterance genid="9" time="14 January 2013 04:51">From a (mostly) layman&amp;#39;s perspective, I&amp;#39;d like to know what is keeping the exchange rate so high. The company I work at (we make electronic controllers to order) benefited enormously from the drop in exchange rate in the year following the crisis as local companies thought twice about taking their business to India and China. Can that be replicated? If not, why not?I suppose it has something to do with the tight supply of money from the BoE?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Richard Britton">
            <Utterance genid="10" time="28 January 2013 16:47">the graph clearly shows that in virtually every recession the UK economy has returned to pre recession levels of GDP no later than 50 months after the dipwhat then is the reason for the continuing flat lining in this recession? And is there in fact a substantial finite probability that the graph will take a turn downwards again?Certain, rather pessimistic, commentators have predicted recently that there will be a significant devaluation due to artificially low interest rates and other factors. Could they be right? Instead of the paltry 1% GDP growth predicted here and in other places, is there a significant risk of further contraction?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Jayarava">
            <Utterance genid="11" time="9 April 2013 07:12">What&amp;#39;s the margin of error on that 0.1% figure?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="hajjandumrah">
            <Utterance genid="12" time="11 April 2013 04:29">I recently came across your blog and have been reading along. I thought I would leave my first comment. I dont know what to say except that I have enjoyed reading. Nice blog. I will keep visiting this blog very often.flights to Umrahcheap flight to jeddahflights to jeddahumrah jeddah flightsumrah flights from Londoncheap flights to umrah</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Stephan White">
            <Utterance genid="13" time="26 April 2013 04:28">Its just a pity the last government didn&amp;#39;t leave anything on the tank for them to do that! Glyn Willmoth</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
