<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>European labour markets: six key lessons from the Commission report</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="25873a34-293c-11e2-b277-000f20980440"/>
        <Person nickname="Jonathan Harris"/>
        <Person nickname="hmsdandy"/>
        <Person nickname="Simon"/>
        <Person nickname="Calvin Brock"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="25873a34-293c-11e2-b277-000f20980440">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="15 January 2013 15:59">I don&amp;#39;t understand why they froze the minimum wage for young people, seems like a poor choice to me.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Jonathan Harris">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="16 January 2013 02:14">Both points made in the article&amp;#39;s introduction sound correct.  Firstly, that this analysis is useful and secondly that the contents of the report, or at least its summary, as outlined above deserve greater coverage and distribution.In the context of the tone and nature of current political debate about all matters European in the UK, it seems that any analysis apparently coming from the EU, especially institutions is likely to be dismissed out of hand, or receive a mostly hostile reception in the media, no matter how valid, correct, important or informative.Perhaps UK labour and employment market policy think tanks could take up the cause?The Resolution Foundation, Institute for Employment Studies and the Work Foundation all come to mind, though others could be equally valid.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="hmsdandy">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="18 January 2013 05:42">On point 4, it seems like the best solution would be to make it easier to fire everyone, without any discrimination. One of the biggest reasons for youth unemployment is presumably that older generations have protections extended to them which don&amp;#39;t apply to younger workers (it&amp;#39;s difficult to have protection from redundancy when you can&amp;#39;t get a job to begin with). Losing your job is a terrible thing, but it&amp;#39;s no less terrible if you can&amp;#39;t get a job in the first place. We shouldn&amp;#39;t be artificially protecting unproductive older workers from redundancy while younger, more productive workers, are forced into unemployment.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Simon">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="18 January 2013 10:45">Agree there should be no discrimination based on age when it comes to workers&amp;#39; protection, but surely making it easier to fire everyone only further diminishes the security and therefore bargaining position of workers, resulting in greater exploitation by employers -longer working hours, reduced pay, below inflation wage rises, worse working conditions etc - as resistance to any of these by individuals would simply result in being fired. Rather, the knowledge/fear of this and threat it poses is likely to cause most workers not to resist/complain at all. Perhaps laws should be clarified so that firing poor, unproductive workers is made much easier (based on evidence), rather than making it easier to fire everyone, thus reducing the possibility of the possible exploitation described above since workers (the good ones!)would retain their bargaining power.   </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Calvin Brock">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="21 February 2013 02:38">Easily, the article is actually the best topic on this registry related issue. I fit in with your conclusions and will eagerly look forward to your next updates. Just saying thanks will not just be sufficient, for the fantasti c lucidity in your writing. I will instantly grab your rss feed to stay informed of any updates. employment screening</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
