<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>Robert Chote on the irrelevance of the credit rating agencies</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Mark Allan"/>
        <Person nickname="Primula Monkey"/>
        <Person nickname="eventagency11"/>
        <Person nickname="jredw"/>
        <Person nickname="Calvin Brock"/>
        <Person nickname="tom cruise"/>
        <Person nickname="Event staff"/>
        <Person nickname="hugh jackman"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Mark Allan">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="6 December 2012 10:46">Osbourne used the triple A credit rating and the retention of it as a justification to push through his oxymoronic &amp;quot;expansionary fiscal contraction&amp;quot;. Telling any who would listen that the markets would crucify us if we lost it.Now it looks as though we might,well it&amp;#39;s not such a big deal after all now,he says.What a imbecilic,useless chancellor he is.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Primula Monkey">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="7 December 2012 07:13">If it is lost and the market response, measured by the change in UK borrowing costs, was &amp;quot;meh&amp;quot; (which it obviously would be) , then one of the primary justifications for current government policy would look a tad silly. As would the chancellor - so either it does matter and he&amp;#39;s the man who lost our coveted AAA status or it doesnt and its a u-turn after inflicting avoidable pain.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="eventagency11">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="9 December 2012 23:12">It feels so nice to find somebody with some original thoughts on this subjectEvent Staffing AgencyReally thankful to you for starting this. </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="jredw">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="10 December 2012 04:50">And if further evidence of the ratings agencies being a lagging indicator were required:http://fivethirtyeight.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/08/08/why-s-p-s-ratings-are-substandard-and-porous/The 10yr UK Gilt yields about 1.73%... markets have already priced in a protracted period of low growth with no apparent fears of outright default (or implicit default through inflation)</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Calvin Brock">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="10 December 2012 06:08">credit is issued. We will look at how programs outside higher education&amp;#8212;as well as some pioneering projects in the postsecondary sphere&amp;#8212;are adopting microcredentials and badge-empowered learning. 3 credit reports</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="tom cruise">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="4 March 2013 19:52">I find many useful things herewithEvent staffing agency</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Event staff">
            <Utterance genid="7" time="3 April 2013 20:13">Hi, what a great web blogeventstaffing</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="hugh jackman">
            <Utterance genid="8" time="28 April 2013 21:33">nice blog with some nice informationevent staffing agency</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
