<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>What Is Wrong with the UK Economy? A guest blog by Adam Posen</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="David Wishart"/>
        <Person nickname="paulc156"/>
        <Person nickname="darzil"/>
        <Person nickname="Mombasa"/>
        <Person nickname="James Ron"/>
        <Person nickname="John Matthew"/>
        <Person nickname="Saibancho"/>
        <Person nickname="John"/>
        <Person nickname="William Martin"/>
        <Person nickname="julieshans02"/>
        <Person nickname="stricvan33"/>
        <Person nickname="Robat Jonson"/>
        <Person nickname="fspeople"/>
        <Person nickname="elba paul"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="David Wishart">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="14 December 2012 05:58">Mr. Posen makes a number of strong arguments, closing the door on many of the failed UK government policies...and then reopens it just a crack with the last paragraph. Why provide Conservatives with that kind of opening to frame the debate as a debt and deficit problem when that&amp;#39;s clearly not an issue for a sovereign government with its own free-floating currency. The government and BOE will always be able to shuffle balances around between Gilts and Reserves through computer keystrokes. They don&amp;#39;t face a solvency constraint so stop pretending they do. And deficits only matter when the economy is chugging along at full employment because now the government spending begins competing with the private sector for a scarce pool of employees and resources. The UK is nowhere near that point. What Mr. Posen needs to be saying is that tomorrow&amp;#39;s consumption can only be funded by tomorrow&amp;#39;s production. If we fail to invest now, we won&amp;#39;t have the productive investments in place to provide the means to enjoy future consumption. Hoarding/Saving pound sterling denominated financial claims is actually counterproductive because it ensures we don&amp;#39;t make the necessary investments towards tomorrow&amp;#39;s technology and productive capacity. All this savings is actually pushing us backwards. The Conservative argument has the causality all backwards. Investment creates savings, not the other way around. We invest, which creates jobs, and those new worker&amp;#39;s gather savings as they wait for the final products of those investments to come online. The UK debt is no different than a savings account at a retail bank. You move money from your checking account (reserves) to your savings account (Gilts). So if you want a change in policy, stop playing in to the Conservative hand by ever framing the debate like there is a government debt or deficit problem.  </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="paulc156">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="14 December 2012 06:04">Doesn&amp;#39;t this suggest rather that capitalism itself is grinding evermore to a slow but inevitable halt?Particularly here in the UK we have a dominant financial sector focused on international transfers and government subsidised channeling of funds [pensions, ISA&amp;#39;s etc]facilitated by a network of crown dependencies and dodgy tax jurisdictions which neither seeks nor needs British industry, hence our wretched debt-load on households and smaller business which will impinge on domestic orientated growth for another decade or longer. Public investment is worthwhile if it&amp;#39;s direct and not fed through private industry whereupon it can be relied upon to wind up in shareholders accounts, executive pay hikes and zero rated hideaways. Future private investment is bound to accentuate the longer term problems too, by increasing the capital based nature of such investment leaving a residual army of un/under-employed to fester ultimately forcing down profit margins even further eventually choking off investment. If the state doesn&amp;#39;t direct it [investment] and it is no more than an expedient to alleviate GDP figures and debt/GDP ratios without fundamentally altering the inevitable long term trend toward immiseration and redundancy for larger and larger sections of the community-leading who knows where?  </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="darzil">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="15 December 2012 13:10">Is there also an impact of the popular media / politicians telling everyone for the last several years how bad everything was going to get? Most friends I know who lost jobs in the downturn lost them because profitable companies wanted to shed jobs before the downturn hit them too hard, rather than because they were in difficulty now.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Mombasa">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="18 December 2012 03:54">This comment has been removed by the author.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Mombasa">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="18 December 2012 03:56">The UK economy collapsed in 2008, and was in serious trouble before that, as is the rest of the global economy.The current UK coalition is trying to rebalance our economy, but with total debt levels of the UK over 500% of GDP, which makes us the second most indebted nation out side of the USA, and no global demand for goods, another crash is inevitable, but at least the UK may not be the hardest hit, just like the 1930&amp;#39;s Great Depression, the UK has already taken a lot of pain, as the UK did in the 1920&amp;#39;s before the Great Depression started.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="James Ron">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="19 December 2012 03:13">I agree with you completely,I just want to say that Taxing business profits is a low down sneaky way to tax the poor. The business will simply raise the cost of their products or else they will go out of business.Empower Network</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="John Matthew">
            <Utterance genid="7" time="19 December 2012 22:43">Its good to be here, very nice post, the content is amazing, keep posting friend it will be very helpful for everyone, Thanks for sharing. I really liked it.PPI Claims Made Simple</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Saibancho">
            <Utterance genid="8" time="20 December 2012 03:01">Interesting Post. Posen states at the end of an article on him in the NYT that there are 3 options of the table for the UK.Austerity, Stimulus and Do Nothing. Austerity seems not to be working even on the most superfiial of analyses (and may even be the very thing which is deepening the crisis rather than aiding recovery), Do Nothing is clearly a bad idea, and so we are left with Stimulus...its what kind of stimulus and how to apply it intelligently that should be the focus of the governments economic policies in the UK. Would you agree with this in general?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="John">
            <Utterance genid="9" time="11 January 2013 03:51">Well, is it as simple as public spending versus cuts? We can check this by looking at the data for the UK economy for the past 65 years and look at the relationship between public spending and GDP in the UK. We have had plenty of booms and busts so increased spending should precede recoveries and decreased spending precede downturns. I have plotted the data at:Does public spending stimulate the economy?What I found surprised me. Increasing public sector spending seems tobe bad whenever it exceeds private sector growth. Take a look at thegraphs in the link above.  It happens every time over the past 70 years. If you want to improve the economy, in the UK at least, your simplest action is to cut public spending, or so it appears. Any comments?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="William Martin">
            <Utterance genid="10" time="8 March 2013 02:08">woow  . valuable post . thanks for sharing.Financial Claims Made Simple</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="julieshans02">
            <Utterance genid="11" time="25 March 2013 12:57">Pension leads can be a very difficult process,especially if beginning without a definite plan of action.The results of Granger causality test show that higher saving and investment lead to better economic growth. Pension leads</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="stricvan33">
            <Utterance genid="12" time="7 April 2013 13:44">Bigest brokers want the best for you? Groups to join and we can see how that could happen along with investors. Investment leads to highly responsive, high-security proposal and portfolio income.investment leads</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Robat Jonson">
            <Utterance genid="13" time="12 April 2013 22:42">Thanks a lot for distribution these in arrange I&amp;#39;ve forever been on the guard for the position and laws of lodging in USA since I&amp;#8217;m preparation to spend present in the prospect.mortgage banker</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="fspeople">
            <Utterance genid="14" time="8 May 2013 03:50">Thanks for sharing your views with us. I think now I have a strong hold over the topic after going through the post. I will surely come back for more information. Please gone through my site also http://www.fspeople.com/</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="elba paul">
            <Utterance genid="15" time="16 May 2013 02:26">Interesting content, finance for starting small business is very important, I find this share very crucial because I like run my enterprise soon and I&amp;#39;m sure it will obviously be complicated.Small Business Loans</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
