<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>The (economic) objectives of immigration policy: a dialogue with Martin Wolf</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Homer Paxton"/>
        <Person nickname="starcourse"/>
        <Person nickname="Gary"/>
        <Person nickname="John H"/>
        <Person nickname="Oldsoul_NotQuite"/>
        <Person nickname="sachin tanwar"/>
        <Person nickname="Stephan White"/>
        <Person nickname="Regional College Of Pharmacy"/>
        <Person nickname="Mary Brawn"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Homer Paxton">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="4 April 2013 20:07">you are appreciated downunder.please keep it up</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="starcourse">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="5 April 2013 01:22">What about the impact of immigration on democracy and social cohesion?  This has very significant implications for the medium- and long-term development of the country.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Gary">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="5 April 2013 06:38">Very interesting and enlightening. I am  very  pleased that Martin Wolf mentions the tradeable/non-tradeable implications. Immigration (especially temporary) is linked to employment, training, human capital accumulation, and trade in services. One of my biggest concerns is that the UK  has made it far too easy to bring in skills rather develop them in the UK.I disagree with Martin Wolf on prioritizing scientific and technical graduates. I think that is probably based in the shortage myth.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="John H">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="5 April 2013 09:03">I find your assumption that the welfare of foreigners should have a zero weight very surprising. One implication: we should give no foreign aid at all. Do you accept that this is an implication, do you accept that we should give no foreign aid or do you deny the assumption that the welfare of foreigners should have zero weight?By the way, the revealed preferences of British voters is an extremely inadequate way to weight the welfare of others. By the same token, if British voters and parents decided to spend no money whatsoever on children, this would blatantly not show that the weighting of children&amp;#39;s welfare should be zero. The (in my view inadequate) reason for revealed preference valuations of welfare is some kind of idea of consumer sovereignty: i.e. how do individuals value their own welfare? This requirement is not satisfied by examining the preferences of British voters.John</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Oldsoul_NotQuite">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="5 April 2013 12:08">It would be helpful if you both would comment/ propose an economically coherent/ workable approach to deciding who is a high skilled vs. low skilled migrant. Jonathan, you hint at one in the form of high skilled migrants fulfilling the condition that their &amp;quot;taxes paid &amp;gt; benefits consumed&amp;quot;. Martin you hint at another in arguing that the distributional impact of immigrants on low skilled indigenous workers should be taken into account (by implication we should protect segments of the indigenous labour force). I see problems with both approaches:The taxes &amp;gt; benefits approach must be estimated across the total time a migrant spends in the UK. Those educated at their own expense, young/ hard-working, infertile (!) and willing to leave upon retirement would be winners. But can we really predict any of this, are there actuarial tables to do so. And would this not miss the odd Nobel laureate/ great entrepreneur.The protect the indigenous approach doesn&amp;#39;t, to my mind, have much to do with skills. Why not protect anyone whose income is affected. Also should we reverse this for owners of capital who may benefit from migrant labourers at the margin? Lastly, does the Gary Becker approach of auctioning residence/work permits address the issues you describe with an efficient solution?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="sachin tanwar">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="11 April 2013 02:57">This is very impressive post with every minute details mentioned and clearly expressed,great job.Immigration Consultants in Chandigarh</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Stephan White">
            <Utterance genid="7" time="26 April 2013 04:34">nice blog. thanks for sharing. Glyn Willmoth</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Regional College Of Pharmacy">
            <Utterance genid="8" time="26 April 2013 22:27">Your blog is very informative and gracefullyyour guideline is very good.Thank youEngineering college Best engineering college in india Private engineering college  pharmacy college    pharmacy college in india top pharmacy college   Polytechnic college Top polytechnic college Top private polytechnic college  Top polytechnic colleges in India Techanical collegesPolytechnic college in indiaLeading call center Outbound call center indiaCheap Seo services india</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Mary Brawn">
            <Utterance genid="9" time="6 May 2013 20:19">Simple mobile payment Simple Mobile | Net10 Wireless | h2O Wireless Online Payments , Payment Center Prepaid pay by phone, Spot Mobile, Red Pocket, Ultra Mobile. Payment Center.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
