<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>The Austerity Delusion?</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Richard"/>
        <Person nickname="Roddy"/>
        <Person nickname="Aditya"/>
        <Person nickname="Unknown"/>
        <Person nickname="Ricardo&amp;amp;#39;s Ghost"/>
        <Person nickname="John"/>
        <Person nickname="matthew859"/>
        <Person nickname="Lefty Lampton"/>
        <Person nickname="ray564k"/>
        <Person nickname="Simon"/>
        <Person nickname="daviesp856"/>
        <Person nickname="Andrew Boada"/>
        <Person nickname="Postkey"/>
        <Person nickname="jimmi korbet"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Richard">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="27 January 2013 13:26">I think most of these problems relate to the lack of everyone using the same clear definitions. When that happens we get people making stuff up to fit their prejudices. Of course it makes no sense to think of a ratio of GDP, which is the fiscal deficit as a fiscal stimulus per se. To do that would mean that if a tsunami hit Japan and GDP plunged, they would be considered to be stimulating the economy even if current spending was constant. The government using discretionary fiscal measures would be a fair definition of fiscal stimulus. Targeted tax cuts or additional spending are both fiscal stimulus. However, I think it is a pretty weak argument to say that the absence of fiscal stimulus is austerity. So although some people are calling spending stimulus when it is not, others are using very weak definitions for austerity. What do we call the halfway house between not cutting total managed expenditure and not stimulating? That seems to me where we are in the UK. If the anti-austerity argument is the government fiscal decisions are negatively impacting national GDP, and that usually is the argument. Only criticisms of the cuts in public sector capital spending and the VAT rise make much sense with regards to negative impact on national GDP. All the micro impacts of some departments spending being cut and some increasing are pretty much cancelling each other out in GDP terms. Therefore, the lack of a clear definition for what is meant by austerity leads to the situation of people concluding there is no austerity if total spending is rising.The rail fares issue could have been dealt with by moving away from rail fares increasing using the discredited RPI calculation. Moreover, the government are wasting at least &amp;#163;3 billion a year on extra debt interest payments on index-linked gilts using the same discredited RPI. A bonus for international investors and usually prosperous domestic pensioners, but an unnecessary cost for taxpayers. Surely the government could find a more productive use for that &amp;#163;3 billion while at the same time the impact on total spending would be neutral.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Roddy">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="28 January 2013 02:24">Right off your main thrust, so possibly OT, but what commodity prices, over what period, what effect, are you referring to in last para?  Just in brief.It startled me as I wasn&amp;#39;t aware, depending on your starting point(s) over the volatile late noughties of course, that commodities had been contractionary.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Aditya">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="28 January 2013 03:48">In one of your previous blogs, I cannot remember which, you had a chart showing the decline in real government purchases. I thought that was a terrific demonstration of how austerity has happened, since the decline in purchases has been offset by increased safety-net expenditures if one looks at the overall view.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Unknown">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="28 January 2013 07:22">Triple dip here we come</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Richard">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="28 January 2013 10:14">&amp;quot;According to the OBR, between 2009-10 and 2011-12 taxes went up by more than 1 percent of GDP, while public investment fell by 1.7 percent of GDP.&amp;quot;Hi Jonathan - do you have a link to this?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Ricardo&amp;amp;#39;s Ghost">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="28 January 2013 15:51">Andrew Lilico from Europe Economics has responded:http://conservativehome.blogs.com/platform/2013/01/andrew-lilico-what-jonathan-portes-gets-wrong-and-why.html</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="John">
            <Utterance genid="7" time="29 January 2013 02:52">If government stimuli can indeed rescue an economy then there should be a record somewhere in the data of increasing public spending increasing private sector growth. Does public spending ever increase private sector growth?  If Keynes was right then there must be a record somewhere in the UK and US data of a public spending binge that stimulated industry.If you look at the actual data, it is surprising, see: Sydenhams Law of public expenditure and GDP growthWhether the public spending is for wars, economic intervention or welfare the answer is NO, furthermore the New Deal seems to have been a myth, there was a strong private sector recovery in the USA before the New Deal.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="matthew859">
            <Utterance genid="8" time="29 January 2013 03:57">&amp;#8220;But any credible analysis suggests that pretending that there has not in fact been a sharp fiscal consolidation in the UK, with predictably adverse consequences, is equally mistaken. &amp;#8220;There obviously has been fiscal consolidation in the UK since 2010. How much effect this has had on growth and job creation is the real debate. The other factors mentioned, (Euro austerity, Oil etc) probably had significantly more impact on growth than fiscal consolidation in my view.The &amp;#8220;predictably adverse consequences&amp;#8221; you mention is where I would disagree the most. The level of employment and jobless claims are far more important to the majority of the population than the notoriously inaccurate (in the near term) and revised statistical composite that it is GDP.Judging the economy on the GDP alone would seem to be rather unwise. The consistent record of large revisions to data from previous recessions and the issues the ONS has experienced since 2008 will probably make the data even less reliable than normal.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Lefty Lampton">
            <Utterance genid="9" time="29 January 2013 06:01">The &amp;quot;Definition of Austerity&amp;quot; debate has predictably and rapidly descended into angels-on-pinheads territory. Lilico&amp;#39;s blog yesterday was a masterpiece in pedantic semantics obscuring the core content of the discussion.It really doesn&amp;#39;t matter whether the current fiscal position equates to &amp;quot;Austerity&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Stimulus&amp;quot; by one person&amp;#39;s idiosyncratic definition. What matters is what the effect of the fiscal position is.But the Consolidators have a very persuasive and simple argument in claiming that the fact that our current high deficit AND lack of growth &amp;quot;proves&amp;quot; that fiscal stimulus does not work. It seems to me that those who veer more to the Keynesian outlook require an equally simple and persuasive argument.How about the following metaphor.You are driving a car and the road starts to go uphill. You respond by pushing the accelerator harder. The car more or less maintains speed but you now start to worry about your fuel consumption. So you ease off the pedal a little and the car stalls. But when the car stalled, you were still pushing the pedal harder than you would have done on a level road. Do you conclude that pushing the pedal harder than normal cannot get you up a hill?That, in a nutshell, appears to be the Redwood/Lilico approach.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="ray564k">
            <Utterance genid="10" time="29 January 2013 07:22">Andrew Lilico has indeed responded- googled to find out who he was and this gem came up:http://www.thisismoney.co.uk/money/news/article-1702363/Interest-rates-may-reach-8-by-2012.html10% inflation by 2012... </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Simon">
            <Utterance genid="11" time="29 January 2013 08:13">It is a misnomer to actually call Lilico&amp;#39;s blog yesterday a &amp;#39;response&amp;#39;. Rather as it is a mass of misdirection, misinterpretation and as LL (above) states &amp;quot;a masterpiece in pedantic semantics obscuring the core content of the discussion&amp;quot;, in which his own opinions,definitions and obscurely constructed interpretations disprove and supposedly trump many of the arguments in Portes&amp;#39; original article. He begins by raising the question of bias on the part of the NIESR. Take a quick look at the title of his webpage (Conservativehome)! I&amp;#39;m sure he thinks he has written an unbiased &amp;#39;response&amp;#39;.On the question of the deficit reduction plan, his argument becomes laughable, where he firstly cites Portes &amp;quot;He claims the causality runs the other way - deficit reduction stalled and therefore the government abandoned its deficit reduction targets.  But there&amp;#39;s no economic causality there.The government wasn&amp;#39;t obliged to abandon its deficit reduction targets because of stalling deficit reduction by anything other than politics.  With full policy freedom, the government could have cut spending faster, to keep to its targets.  Deficit reduction is stalling because the government has stopped trying to cut the deficit.&amp;quot;So the government&amp;#39;s own policies have nothing to do with the missed deficit targets? Self-defeating austerity policies as highlighted by numerous other economic bodies and studies have not reduced tax receipts and caused various forms of G, including transfer payments to rise? It has simply been through policy choice alone to abandon the deficit reduction plan? The target could have been kept if the government had cut spending faster? So a greater dose of poison would fix the patient then.I&amp;#39;ll leave the rest to Jonathan and perhaps others, as its simply not worth spending any more time on this. </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="daviesp856">
            <Utterance genid="12" time="29 January 2013 08:25">The left will never admit that the public sector became far too bloated to be sustainable by the Taxpayer which had to fund hence having a massive structural deficit towards the latter part of a boom (I don&amp;#39;t think Keynes would have approved of that Mr Brown).The facts are quite simple.  Put aside the complexities you talk about or whether you are left or right or whether or not cuts contribute to growth it is patently obvious that we are still living way beyond our means.  If you cut capital spending unless you are replacing or automating a function the taxpayer incurs costs later on so using that argument is short term.If you cut day to day department spending those departments must learn to live within their means, it happens all the time in business, public servants often don&amp;#39;t have these skills (I&amp;#39;ve seen it first hand) so by definition if it leads to a small cut in the size of the economy (and there are varying shades of opinion on this) further down the line it will always lead to financial stability.If your theory that borrowing and splurging (making out the likes of Redwood etc were evil) was right then why did the UK economy go into decline before the banking crises?  If you stealth tax and regulate everyone to death then all you do is scare business away.  You are also forgetting that if they don&amp;#39;t stop printing money to fund this borrowing we are heading for big inflationary trouble which will impact us all - by this definition the cuts and EU red tape have been nowhere near what they need to be.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Andrew Boada">
            <Utterance genid="13" time="2 February 2013 03:53">It doesn&amp;#39;t take long for the austerity crowd to reveal that their austerity policies aren&amp;#39;t rooted in sound macroeconomics (they aren&amp;#39;t) but in their social values and theory of state. They don&amp;#39;t like the welfare state and they see scaremongering over the deficit and the debt as their opportunity to pare it down. </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Postkey">
            <Utterance genid="14" time="2 February 2013 14:21">Distinguish between discretionary and induced {cyclical} expenditures.The government have chosen to cut capital expenditure. {Discretionary expenditure}.See June Budget 2010 P45 This, of course, has adverse effects on GDP, leading to falling tax revenues and increases in induced {cyclical} expenditures.**This would lead to current public spending rising in cash and real terms?According to S.Keen:In the USA, in the&amp;#160; &amp;#39;Great Depression&amp;#39; aggregate demand fell and GDP declined by 28%. &amp;#160;In the USA, in the&amp;#160; &amp;#39;Great Recession&amp;#39;, aggregate demand fell by a greater amount than it had in the &amp;#39;Great Depression&amp;#39; but GDP declined by&amp;#160; &amp;#39;only&amp;#39; 5%.http://www.scribd.com/doc/116293469/Keen-2012-Fiscal-Cliff-Lessons-From-1930-sThe initial increase in discretionary expenditures {plus induced expenditures} prevented, in this case, the U.S. economy falling by more than 28%. **{The government were expecting the Barro/Ricardo equivalence proposition to generate extra aggregate demand? The new &amp;#39;Voodoo Economics&amp;#39;?}     </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="jimmi korbet">
            <Utterance genid="15" time="27 April 2013 07:41">It&amp;#8217;s arduous to seek out knowledgeable people on this matter, but you sound like you already know what you&amp;#8217;re talking about! Thanksmoving services California</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="jimmi korbet">
            <Utterance genid="16" time="4 May 2013 00:06">I find many useful things herewithmoving companies california</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
