<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><Dialog>
    <Topics>When it comes to migration, there are no winners in the numbers game</Topics>
    <Participants>
        <Person nickname="Mark"/>
        <Person nickname="B.H."/>
        <Person nickname="un"/>
        <Person nickname="FPPeterson"/>
        <Person nickname="hajjandumrah"/>
        <Person nickname="Rihana Gomez"/>
    </Participants>
    <Body>
        <Turn nickname="Mark">
            <Utterance genid="1" time="5 April 2013 01:50">I think that&amp;#39;s the point... After the disaster with the Polish estimates, people have learnt it is nigh on impossible to predict how many will come.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="B.H.">
            <Utterance genid="2" time="6 April 2013 00:16">I am Romanian and I tell you, they won&amp;#8217;t come. You, Brits, are paranoid or infatuated with yourself. And remember, Romania was never part of the mighty British Empire. Probably that is what really bothers you.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="un">
            <Utterance genid="3" time="6 April 2013 03:43">Migrants may under use public services when they first arrive but once they have children the situation changes. They are entitled to substantial in work child benefits and the children require schools. If the immigrants are in low paid jobs they will pay insufficient tax to cover the costs of public facilities they will use over their lifetime.I fail to see how the influx of low-paid migrants into the UK, whether from outside the EU or within it, benefits existing residents.  </Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="FPPeterson">
            <Utterance genid="4" time="6 April 2013 12:33">Of course one of the pieces in the &amp;#39;numbers game&amp;#39; which is rarely discussed by Immigrationists is the capital cost of an immigrant, in terms of the infrastructure that needs to be in place for him to function economically from the day of arrival.Few immigrants except perhaps the occasional oligarch arrive with sufficient capital to offset their share of the cost of the accumulated infrastructure that they use, and even fewer will create sufficient added value during their working lifetime to pay for it either.</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="FPPeterson">
            <Utterance genid="5" time="6 April 2013 14:26">The NIESR report certainly looks to be an impressive piece of work even if the authors are understandably reluctant to take a Dustmannesque stab at the likely number of A2 entrants starting in 2014.I was curious however about one particular aspect of the report. There are several references to the effect that the report &amp;quot;... was commissioned to provide evidence from which the UK Government can assess the potential impacts of migration from EU2 countries.&amp;quot;Does this mean that it was commissioned by the government, and if so, which department(s)? If not, who did commission it?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="un">
            <Utterance genid="6" time="8 April 2013 05:44">I find it difficult to avoid the conclusion that the default position of the liberal establishment is&amp;quot;immigration is a good thing&amp;quot;. Any opposition prompts a call for evidence but repeating the establishment line does not.The last paragraph of the article above demonstrates this. It is full of confident assertions about the benefits of immigration, even low-wage immigration. But where is the evidence for such confident assertions? Where is the evidence that existing residents have benefited from low-wage immigration?</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="hajjandumrah">
            <Utterance genid="7" time="8 April 2013 23:29">I recently came across your blog and have been reading along. I thought I would leave my first comment. I dont know what to say except that I have enjoyed reading. Nice blog. I will keep visiting this blog very often.flights to Umrahcheap flight to jeddahflights to jeddahumrah jeddah flightsumrah flights from Londoncheap flights to umrah</Utterance>
        </Turn>
        <Turn nickname="Rihana Gomez">
            <Utterance genid="8" time="11 April 2013 07:26">It compares the economic profile of an overwhelmingly young (and single) migrant group with &amp;#8216;natives&amp;#8217;, that is: a much larger cohort with entirely different demographic characteristics and correspondingly variegated need to call upon particular elements of the benefits system. The &amp;#8216;native&amp;#8217; cohort also includes the offspring of other recent migrant groups whose overall fiscal contribution may or may not be congruent with that of the actual indigenous population (other evidence suggests it is not). It would have been far more useful if Dustmann et al had used a &amp;#8216;native&amp;#8217; cohort with comparable age and family status characteristics for their comparator. A further, perhaps, minor point that might have borne more emphasis is that, during the entire period under review (2004-2009) A8 entrants were denied benefits for their first twelve months, effectively reducing the pool of potential A8 claimants by 20% overall.The term &amp;#8216;state benefits&amp;#8217; is not well-defined either. There is a entire panoply of &amp;#8216;in work&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;out of work&amp;#8217; benefits to which A8 workers were and are entitled. Most &amp;#8216;natives&amp;#8217; will be unaware of the full scope and scale of the system but A8 entrants might well be better-informed, especially with helpful websites like this one to guide them through the thicket (similar websites are now springing up in Romanian and Bulgarian).Watch tons of videos on You-YouTube. Share You YouTube videos with friends, family, and the world. Collection of the Best Videos on You-YouTube.The latest music videos, short movies, tv shows, funny and extreme videos. Upload, share, and embed your videos. Watch premium and official videos free online. Discover our featured content. http://you-youtube.com</Utterance>
        </Turn>
    </Body>
</Dialog>
